So, what is TypeScript?
TypeScript, is not an entirely new language, it's a super
set of JavaScript, so that means any valid JavaScript code is
also valid TypeScript code, but TypeScript has additional
features that do not exist in the current version of JavaScript
supported by most browsers out there. For example,
in TypeScript we have this concept of strong or static typing,
if you have worked with languages like C# and Java, you will know that in these
languages, when we define the variable, we need to specify the type of
that variable. Now, in TypeScript, typing is optional, so we don't have to use
this feature. But using this feature, makes our applications more
predictable, and it also makes it easier to debug them when something
goes wrong. TypeScript also brings quite a few object oriented
features that we have missed in JavaScript for a long time. We have
the concept of Classes, Interfaces, Constructors,
Access Modifiers, like public and private, Fills, Properties,
Generics and so on. You're going to learn about this in this section.
Now, another benefit of using TypeScript is that with TypeScript we
catch errors at Compile-time, instead of Run-time, but of course
not all kinds of errors, but a lot of errors. So there is a compilation
step involved, and when we compile our TypeScript code, we can catch these errors
and fix them before deploying our application. And finally,
another benefit of using TypeScript, is that we get access to
some great tools out there. One thing I personally love about TypeScript is
the intelligence that we get in our code editors. Again,
you're going to see that in this section. So TypeScript is a beautiful language
and it's basically a superset of JavaScript, so any valid JavaScript code
is also valid TypeScript code. Now, the browsers out there,
they don't understand TypeScript, and it's very unlikely that they're going to support it
in the future, so we need to compile for more accurately,
so we Transpile our TypeScript code, into JavaScript.
So, this is part of building our application, whenever we build our application,
TypeScript compiler kicks in, and it Transpiles
our TypeScript code into JavaScript code our browsers can understand.
Now, that's enough introduction. Next I'm going to show you how to install
TypeScript, and write your first TypeScript program.