In this lecture, I'm going to show you how to install
TypeScript, and write your first TypeScript program. So here,
in the terminal, we're not going to work with Angular in this section, we're going to purely
focus on TypeScript. So first we need to install TypeScript
globally on our machine. So, npm,
install -g, which stands for global, typescript.
And of course, if you're on Mac, you need to put sudo at the
front. Alright,
beautiful, so I've installed the latest version of TypeScript, which is currently
version 2.3.4. Now we can type
tsc, which stands for TypeScript Compiler, --,
version. Again, you can see that I'm running TypeScript,
2.3.4. Alright, now I'm going to create a new folder for
this section, so let's call ts-hello.
Let's go to this folder, now here I'm going to create
a new file, and open it with vs code. So, code
main.ts. So,
now I'm going to write some plain JavaScript code, and I want to show you that all this
JavaScript code is also valid TypeScript code, so first
I'm going to define a function, let's call this log,
that takes a message,
and here we simply log that message on the console,
like this.
Then I'm going to declare a global variable, let's call this
message, and set it to this string, Hello World.
And finally call our log function, message.
So this is just plain JavaScript code, right?
Save, back in the terminal, we need to Transpile
this TypeScript file into JavaScript, so
tsc, or TypeScript Compiler, main.ts.
Now, if you look at the files in this folder, look what we have
main.js, and main.ts. Now this Transpilation,
or compilation step, when you are building an Angular app, happens
under the hood, so you don't have to manually call the TypeScript,
compiler. In fact when you run your application using
ng serve, Angular CLI, calls TypeScript compiler under the hood,
to transpile all of our TypeScript code. Alright, now let's
open our main.js file. So code.main.js.
So it's exactly the same code that we wrote
but now it's in a JavaScript file. So all JavaScript code
is also valid TypeScript code. Now back in the terminal, I
can execute this code using node. So node, main.js
And we got the Hello World message on the console.
So for the next lecture, we're going to look at specific features of
TypeScript that we don't currently have in JavaScript.