Alright, let's explore TypeScript by looking
at Variable Declarations. So in TypeScript,
there are two ways to declare a variable. We can use the var keyboard
which you have seen in JavaScript, like var number, reset it to 1.
Or, we can use the let keyword. So, let, count,
3, 2. Now, before I explain the difference, I
need to clarify that the let keyword is also being added to the JavaScript,
so JavaScript has a few different versions. We have
ES5, or ECMAScript 5, which is the version of JavaScript
supported by pretty much all browsers out there, it's been around for
a long time. Now we have ES6, which is a newer version,
and it was introduced in year 2015, and from that point
the ECMAScript team, which is the team extending JavaScript
decided to use the year number, instead of the version number.
So, we have ECMAScript 2015, 2016, and
2017. Now with ECMAScript 2015, which is basically
ES6, you also have this let keyword. But,
in case you are not familiar with it, let me explain how it works.
So, I'm going to define a function. Let's call it do
Something. It doesn't really matter. But here I'm going to define
a for block, so var we said i to 0,
and as long as i is less than five,
let's increment it, here we have a block and then log it on the console.
Now, finally at the end of this function, I'm going to
log this i one more time. But with the label
Finally.
Then I'm going to call this function here. So,
in the terminal I'm going to compile this file, main.ts, and
also at the same time, run it with node, main.ts,
Note that the value of i at the end
is 5. So this is the issue we have when declaring
a variable using the var keyboard. So we have declared i
here, inside this for block, but it's also meaningful
and available, outside the for block. Now if you have worked with languages
like C Sharp, or Java, you know that we don't have these concepts, and those languages.
In JavaScript, a variable declared with
a var keyboard, is the scope to the nearest function. So in this
case the nearest function is doSomething, so once we declare
i inside this for block, it's available anywhere in this
function. Now let's see what happens when we declare this variable using
the let keyboard. So, let.
Now look, we immediately got a red underline here which indicates
a compilation error. And this is one of the beauties of TypeScript.
When you are writing TypeScript code, you can catch these errors at compile time,
before you run your application, before you deploy it. Now this hover
or mouse here, so this is the error, can not find main, i.
So now i is scope to the nearest log.
instead of nearest function, and this is the proper way to declare
variables which prevents a lot of issues later down the road.
Now, I want to clarify something. I'm going to save this file,
back in the terminal, first I'm going to remove main.
js. Now, I'm going to recompile
our main.ts, okay, we got our error here, can not find
name 'i'. However, if you look at the files
in this folder, we do have main.js, so even though we have a
compilation error, the TypeScript compiler still generated main.
js. Let's have a look at the content of this file.
So this is the code that is generated. So
by default, TypeScript Compiler compiles our TypeScript code to
ES5, or ECMA Script 5, which is the older version of JavaScript
that is supported by all browsers out there. Now there, we don't have
the let keyboard. So, that's why our compile code now
uses the var keyboard, and this is perfectly valid JavaScript code.
So, I can go in the terminal, and simply
run this code and get the same output as before.
So, what I want to clarify here, is that TypeScript
Compiler reports these errors, but still generates
valid JavaScript code. So here's the takeaway for
this lecture: from now on, anywhere we want to declare a variable, we use
the let keyboard. Once again, this does not stop the compilation step,
but at least we can catch the issues earlier during the
compile time. Next, we're going to look at different types we have in TypeScript.