In this lecture, I'm going to show you different types
we have in TypeScript. So, let me start
by declaring a variable, called count, and set it to 5.
Now, if I set this to let's say a
character or a string like 'a', note that I immediately get a
compilation error here, telling me that this 'a' string, or 'a' character,
is not assignable to type number. Now, we can perfectly
do this in JavaScript, because in JavaScript we can change
the type of variables on the fly, but in TypeScript, we get a compilation
error. Now, once again, I want to clarify that we can perfectly compile
this, using TypeScript Compiler and we will get valid JavaScript
code. So, if I go to terminal and type TypeScript
Compiler, main.ts, now look, this is our
main.js, so we have this count variable, and we change it's value.
We can perfectly execute this, no problem. However
code like this is very likely that it's going to break at some point in
the future, because chances are we're going to use this count variable
inside a for block, so our program is going to break at run time.
We don't want this to happen, right? That's one of the reasons it's better to
write the same code in TypeScript so at least we can get a warning
during the compilation step. Now, if you hover your mouse
over this count variable, look at the tool tip.
You can see a colon and number after this count.
So this indicates the type of count variable in our program.
So here, TypeScript Compiler inferred that the type of this variable
should be a number, because we set it to number 5. Now what
if I declare a variable without initializing it? Let's look at
this type. It's type is now any,
and this exactly like the variables that we declare in JavaScript. So we can
set a to 1, and then I can change the value to true and
set it to a string, even TypeScript doesn't complain about this.
So, what's the solution? If you don't know the value of a variable ahead of
time, that's when we use type annotations. So here,
we add colon, and after that we set the type of this variable.
Like, number. And then look, on the third and
fourth lines, we got compilation errors. Now in TypeScript
we have a few different types. So we have number, which can include
any integer or floating point numbers, we have
boolean's, which can be true or false,
we have strings, we have any that you saw
earlier, we have arrays, so let's say we want
to declare an array of numbers. You would use number,
in square brackets. Now, we can optionally
initialize this to an array like this. Or, we can
declare in any array, and with this
we can set this to an array with these values. One,
true, 'a', and false. Of course,
it's not a good practice, we want to avoid this, but I'm telling you what it possible with TypeScript.
Now we also have another type that I absolutely
love, and that's enum, so let's say you're working with a group
of related constants, like colors, so, in plain
and old, or vanilla JavaScript, we would define constant
colors like this, so color red, we can set this to zero.
Constant, ColorGreen, we set this to one,
constant, ColorBlue, set it to two.
Now, this is a little bit verbose. In a lot of object oriented languages, we have
this concept called enum, so we can put all these related
constants in a container. So in TypeScript, we can
can declare an enum like this, enum, all lower case
we give it a name like Color, now curly braces,
and here we set the values. So red, green,
and blue. Then, we can declare a variable,
like background color, and set it to color
dot, now look we have IntelliSense here.
So this tool tip you see here, allows us to complete this code without
remembering all the details. Now this is one of the things I love about TypeScript.
So, let's set the background color to Color.Red.
Now in terms of the values, the first element
here, automatically gets the value of zero, and
each subsequent element gets an incremented value.
So we don't have to explicitly set these. But as a best practice,
it's better to do so, because chances are some time in the future
someone may come here and add a new color here like purple, and then purple
would automatically become 2, and the value of blue would change to
3. So this may break parts of our application. So,
let me revert this by explicitly setting the values
If somebody adds a new color here like purple,
then it will not change the value of blue. Now let me show you
something. Let's compile this code and see how we get enum
in JavaScript. So, TypeScript Compiler,
main.ts.
Look at this piece of code here. This is how we can implement
the concept of enums in JavaScript. You can see it's very complicated.
Now, compare this with how we declare an enum
here. It's much cleaner. So the more you work with TypeScript,
the more you're going to love this language.