In this lecture, I'm going to show you the
concept of Type Assertions in TypeScript, so
I'm going to start by declaring a variable like message, and setting
it to a string. Now here we can type message, dot,
and look, we get this beautiful IntelliSense and
in this tool tip, we can see all the things we can do with a string. So,
all these items with these purple items are functions, for example we have,
this function called endsWith, we can call
this, and see if this message ends, let's say, with c.
And this returns a Boolean. So we can store the result
in another variable like endsWith
C. However, sometimes
TypeScript may be a little bit confused about the type of a variable.
For example, I'm going to remove this initialization here,
and initial it this variable on the second line.
abc. Now look at this type of this message variable.
It's any, because by default when we don't set a value, it's
type is any. Now the problem here, is
if I delete this and type period, look
we don't get that IntelliSense anymore, because endsWith, is something
that we can do with a  string, not with an object of type any.
So, what should we do? In this case, we need to explicitly
tell TypeScript Compiler that this message variable is actually a
string. And this is what we call Type Assertions.
Now, how do we do Type Assertions? There are two ways. One way
is to prefix this variable with angle brackets and
here we put the type, like string, now we need to enclose
both these parts in parenthesis, like
this. Then, if you press period,
we get our beautiful IntelliSense with all the functions or methods available
on string objects. Now, there is also another way
to do a Type Assertion, so,
let's change the name of this variable to alternativeway,
we still have angle brackets, you use message
as string. They're exactly the same,
now approach issues is purely your personal preference, but the first approach
is what you see more in a lot of tutorials and code bases out
there. Now, I just want to clarify something here, this Type Asserion
does not change this type of variable at run time.
In fact, it's not going to restructure that object in memory. It's purely
a way to tell TypeScript Compiler about the type of a variable.
So, we can access the IntelliSense.