Another concept you need to know when using TypeScript
to build Angular applications, is the concept of Arrow
Functions. So in JavaScript, we can declare a function like this,
let log set this to a function,
this function takes a message object,
and simply logs it on the console, like this.
Now in TypeScript, there is a shorter way to define this
function. So, let's call the other one
doLog, now we don't need the function keyboard anymore,
we can simply add the parameters, in this case
message, then we add this arrow, and that's why
we call this an arrow function. And finally, the code block.
So, console.log, message.
Now if your function only has one line, we can even exclude
these curly braces, so we can make this code
a little bit shorter and cleaner like this.
If you have C Sharp you have seen this before, in C# we call this a lambda expression.
In TypeScript, we call it an arrow function, it's exactly the same thing.
Now, if you have one parameter here, you can even exclude the
parenthesis, but I personally don't like this because I think it makes the code
a little bit less readable, so I always like to put my parenthesis
here, to indicate to the reader of this code that these
are the parameters. Now what if you don't have any parameters? You just add
empty parenthesis, but of course here, you don't have the message.
So, if you have not seen this before, get used to it, it's a really
nice and clean way to define functions.