Alright, now let's see how we can use custom
types in TypeScript. So, I'm going to start by declaring a function
like draw point. So this function takes
an x and a y, and simply draws it on
the screen. Now, we don't want to worry about the actual drawing algorithm,
we just want to focus on the signature of this function. Now this function
is not too bad, here we only have two parameters, but sometimes
when we're working with more complex concept, we may end up with a function
that has so many parameters, like this.
This is really, really bad and is something you should avoid at all times.
In those situations, it's very likely that a group of these parameters
maybe all of them, belong to a singular concept,
as an example think of a car. A car has so many different properties,
we don't want to pass all those properties to a function, like drive car.
Instead, you want to encapsulate them inside an object,
and only pass that one object here. So in this example,
instead of passing x and y here t's better to
pass a point object, and then we can call this function
like this, drawPoint, we can give it an
object with two properties, x and y.
So now our function has a cleaner syntax. However,
there is a problem with this implementation. Instead of the point object,
I can pass a person object that has a name property.
And no where here, we're getting a complier time error, but we know
that this code is going to break at run time, because the algorithm
are drawPoint function is expecting x and y properties.
So, what's the solution? Well, let me revert this back,
okay, we've got x and y. So there are two solutions,
to solve this problem. One way is to use what we call
in line annotation. So just like we can annotate this parameter,
with a type like number, we can annotate it with
a custom type, or custom object. So here we add
curly braces to indicate an object, this object
is going to have a property different than x which is a number, and also
another property called y, which is again, a number. So this is
what we call in line annotation. It works fine for
simple cases, but the problem with this, as you can see is
that this is a little bit verbose. Also, chances are
somewhere else might have another function that expects a point object.
We don't want to repeat this object literal in multiple places.
So in those cases, a better approach is to use an interface.
If you work with object oriented program languages like C Sharp and Java,
you know the concept of interfaces. We have the same concept in TypeScript.
And if you have never worked with interfaces, let me show you how they work.
So, on the top, I define an interface,
I'm going to call this point,
curly braces, then I add x as a number,
and y as a number.
So with this interface, I'm defining the shape of an object.
And then, I can simplify this declaration,
and set the type of this parameter to Point.
This is much cleaner, and we can also reuse this in multiple
places. Just one thing, note the naming convention
I used here. So because I'm introducing a custom type,
I've used Pascal naming convention. So the first
letter of every word in the name of the interface should be capitalized.
So here we have upper case P, other lower case p, okay?
So, when using interfaces, always use Pascal naming
convention.