So in the last lecture, we used
an interface to define the shape of a point object.
But there is a problem with this implementation. In object oriented
program languages, we have this concept called Cohesion.
Which basically means, things that are related, should be part of one
unit. They should go together. This is what we call Cohesion.
Now, back to this example. On the top we had used an interface
to define the shape of a point object, and below that, we have a
stand alone function. And this is where we have violated the
Cohesion principle. The concept of drawing a point
is highly related to the structure of a point. It should not be
a separate function. Now, if you're going to build a utility library for working with
points, chances are, you're going to create another function,
like getDistance, that calculates the distance
between two points. So point A, in type point,
and pointB of type Point. And this goes to
code block. Again, we have violated the Cohesion
principle, we have two functions hanging in the air,
separate from the point object. Since these concepts are highly
related, they should be part of one unit. In object oriented
languages, we call that unit a class. A class
groups properties and functions that are highly
related. Now, in this implementation, unfortunately
we can not move these two functions inside our interface.
Because interfaces are purely for declarations.
They can not include an implementation. In other words,
we can not have an algorithm for calculating the distance
between two points or drawing a point inside this interface.
What we can do instead, is to add
a function here, a function declaration,
so we're going to have a draw function that takes no parameters
and returns void, which means
it doesn't return anything. Now you may be asking, why don't we have
this point parameter here? Because of all these members
x, y, and draw are part of one unit, we don't need to
pass x and y as parameters that draw function.
This function can directly access these properties x and y
in the same unit. So, we don't need this parameter here. Now in
interfaces as I said we can not have implementation, we can only have
signature of a function, so with this interface, we are telling TypeScript
Compiler, that our point objects should have two properties, x and y,
and a function called draw. The implementation of that is
somewhere else. So what should we do now to apply the Cohesion
principle here? We need to use a class instead of an interface.
So, on the top, I'm going to change the type to class
and here I' going to replace this comma with a semicolon,
so our point class has three members, the first two
members are what you call fields that we use for storing data.
And the third member is a function, now here in this class we can
have the actual implementation of this draw function.
So, we can simply define it like this. Draw,
and then add all that logic in drawing a point.
Now similarly, we can have another function get
Distance, that returns the distance between this point and
another point, like this.
Again, all that logic will end up here. Now, with this restructuring,
we can see that everything about the point is in one unit
and one class. So we have the coordinate which includes x and y,
and two functions, draw and getDistance. Now,
in object oriented program terms, we refer to these members as
fields, and to these functions as methods. So when a function
is part of a class, we call it a method. Alright, now with this new
implementation, we don't want these two functions hanging in the air.
So, delete. This is a much better
structure. Also, we're not going to call drawPoint like this anymore.
So here's our point class, in the next
lecture, I'm going to show you how to create an object of this type and call
the drawMethod.