Alright, so here's our class, now
let's declare a variable of this type. So let, point
the of type point. And then
we can type point, dot, look, we have this beautifully
IntelliSense, we have two methods, draw, and getDistance,
and two fields, x and y. Now in TypeScript
you also have a concept called property, which is different from
a field, but a lot of people use these terms interchangeably.
Later, in this section, we're going to learn the difference between fields and properties.
Now, if you want to call the draw method, simply call it like this.
So this draw method is now part of the concept of
the point. It's not a function hanging in the air, polluting the global
namespace. Now for this demo I'm going to add a simple
console.log here, and display the coordinates
of this point. So x, now here I want to
add the x field, but we can not use it like this. We
need to prefix it with this dot, so that refers to
this field in this class. And then I'm going to add y is
once again this.y.
Now let's compile and run this program and see what happens.
So tsc, what should we type here,
main.ts, and we can short cut,
by adding this pipe here, type node, and then
main.js. okay? We're going to run
time error. Can not read property draw of
undefined. So this is the problem, when we call
this draw method, this point object was undefined.
Because here, unlike the basic types we have in TypeScript,
like numbers, strings, booleans, we're dealing with a custom type.
When defining an object of a custom type, we need to
explicitly allocate memory to it, how do we do that?
Well, here where we declare the point object
point variable, we initialize it using the new
operator. So this object, is a new point.
And here we add parenthesis.
This is the syntax. Now you can see that we have repeated this point here,
twice so we can make this code a little bit cleaner,
by removing this type adaptation, because
TypeScript Compiler can infer from this assignment here,
that the type of this object is a point object, and
let's verify that, look, you're working with a point object.
Now, one more time, save, so back in the
terminal, TypeScript Compiler, main.ts,
then node main.js,
okay, we didn't get an error, but you can see these x and y fields,
don't have a value, because by default they are undefined.
So, we can get back here and set point.x
to let's say one, and point.y to two.
Now, back in the terminal, TypeScript Compiler
main.ts, actually made a mistake earlier,
of this type operator, we need to use double && on Mac,
I don't know the Windows equivalent, so with this, we can
combine multiple commands. So node, main.js.
Alright, beautiful. X is one,
and y is two. So this is how we use the classes that we define
in our programs. Now I want to highlight something here.
This point here is a class, but this point here is an object.
An object is an instance of a class.
As a metaphor, think of the concept of a human. A human can be a class,
but when we create instances of this class, like Jon, Bob,
Mary, these are all objects. So that's the difference between
a class and an object. Next, we're going to look at Constructors.