Alright, so I've simplified the code from the last
lecture, I simply removed the method, getDistance, because we're not going
to use it later in this section. So here on the top would define a
point class, and then below that initialize a point object. Now this code
is a little bit verbose. Because we have three lines
to create a point object and put it in a valid state.
What if this point object had a few other properties that we had to initialize like
this. Maybe a few
more here. Is there a cleaner way? Absolutely.
So let me delete this first, alright, an object
oriented program languages, we have this concept called
Constructor. So every class can have a Constructor, which is basically
a method that is called when we create an instance of
that class. So, let me show you how it works. In a class,
I'm going to add a method, the name of this method is
Constructor. This is a reserved keyword in TypeScript.
Now this method can have parameters. So x
which is a number, and y, which is also a number.
And then here in this method we can initialize these fields.
So, what should we write here? This, dot,
x, we set it to this x argument that we get here.
And similarly, this, dot, y, we set it to y.
Now look, we got a compilation error here. Because when creating
a new point object, we need to supply these values.
Look at the error: supply parameters do not match any signature
of call target. So here, we need to supply the value
views for x and y, one and two, and with this we can simplify
this code, and get rid of these two extra lines.
Here's the end result. Now what if somewhere
else in our program we don't know the initial coordinate or point?
In other words, what if I want to create a point object
without setting these values, is that possible? Yes, absolutely.
But it's a little different from how you have seen that in
other languages like C Sharp and Java. In C Sharp we can
have multiple Constructors, in TypeScript we can't. So the solution
for this is to make these parameters optional. So here
after x, I add the question mark, and that
makes x optional. And similarly, y should
be optional as well. Because once you make a parameter optional
all the other parameters on the right side of that parameter should be optional also.
This is a rule by TypeScript and other program languages.
So now, look we don't have a compilation error, when creating a point
object without initial values.