Alright, so here I've created a point object,
with an initial coordinate. Now what if in our program, you want to
have this rule such that when we initialize a point object we should
not be able to change the x or y values?
With this implementation, I can always come here and set
point.x to a different value. How can we avoid this?
Sometimes, we need this feature in our programs, because it will make them
more predictable. It reduces the chance for bugs. So,
how should we prevent the coordinate of this project to change after
it's initialized? Well, in object oriented languages we have
these concepts called Access Modifiers.
An Access Modifier, is basically a keyword we can apply to a member of a
class to control it's access from the outside.
So in TypeScript, we have three Access Modifiers, public, private,
and protected. Public and private are the most common, and
by default, all members are public. Let me show you what I mean.
So here, in our point class, we have three members, right?
We have two fields, and one method, so,
let me create a point object, and type point,
dot, look, these are the members of the class, and
because they are all public, we can access them here. And that's why we can see them
in the IntelliSense. However, I can go here,
and prefix this field with the private keyword.
Now, once we create this point
object, if I type point, dot, look
x is not in the list. It's not accessible, it's private.
So if you're trying to set point.x to three, we have a compilation error,
in TypeScript. It says property x is
private, and only accessible within class 'Point'.
Now with this technique, I can go here, and apply
the private keyword on the y field as well.
And now, once I initialize a point object,
I can no longer change it's coordinates, I can only
call the draw method, okay, so this is why we use access
modifiers, we control access to certain members of a class,
from the outside. We can apply these Access Modifiers on fields,
properties and methods. Now by default,
if you don't set an access modifier, it's assumed to be public.
So here, the draw method as you know is public, I can also
add the public keyboard here, but this is redundant, it's just making my
code noisy. So you don't really need to have this, it's better
to keep your code short and clean, and use the private access modifier
only when you need to. Next, I'm going to show you one of my favorite
features of TypeScript, around Access Modifiers.