As you write code with TypeScript, you
see Constructors that follow a pattern like what you see here.
So here we have two parameters in a Constructor and we use these two parameters
to initialize the fields in this class. The code looks a little bit
redundant. This dot x equals x and this dot y equals y.
TypeScript has a fantastic feature that helps you achieve the same thing
with less code. So here, we can
delete these two fields here, and in our Constructor
we can prefix our parameters with an Access
Modifier. So here I want to have, two private fields
x and y, I can simply prefix this
with the private keyword like this.
So TypeScript Compiler will generate these fields for us.
And also, we don't need these ugly
repetitive assignments either. So if you prefix
a Constructor parameter with an access modifier whether private or public
TypeScript Compiler will generate a field with the
exact same name and it will also initialize that field with the value of this argument.
It's one of my favorite features, and you're going to see that a lot
in this course. Now, I'll clarify something before I finish this lecture,
in this case, our fields were private, but if they were public we would
use the pubic keyword here. So this means, when we create
a point object, we can access
the x field. Okay? So,
I'm going to revert this back to the private.