Alright, now this
implementation has a tiny problem. We can set the initial coordinate
of this point, and we can also draw it, but there is no way
for us to read the coordinate, so I can not access point
dot x here to display to the user. What's the work around?
Well, one simple solution is to define a method
like this. getX, and here
simply return this dot x. Because in
this class we do have access to all the private members
of this class, but we can not access them from the outside. Okay?
Now here, I can always call point dot
getX, to get the X value to display to the user
Now let's talk about another use case
Maybe we want to give the user the ability to set the initial coordinate here,
but we also want them to be able to change this coordinate later
only if they provide a value within the given range.
What do I mean by that? Let me show you. I'm going to define
another method here, setX,
Now this method is going to get a value, that's the new
value for the x field. Scroll down,
Now here, first we can do some basic validation. So, if
the value is less than zero, you want to throw an error,
throw new error. Value cannot be
less than zero.
Otherwise, you want to set this dot x to this new value.
Okay? Now with this implementation, we can
always change the value of the x field like this, point
dot set x, set it to a new value
Now if you have a use case like that in your application, you can use what we call
the property. So in TypeScript and
object oriented program languages, we have a concept called Property
which is exactly for this very use case. So,
Look at how I can define a property here. We start with
a keyword which is get or set, and then the name of the Property
which is in this case x, and then after that we're going to have parenthesis.
Just like in method, okay? Now similarly,
I'm going to change this to set, with a space so we have the set keyword
and here it's like we have a function, a method,
Now what is the difference? The difference is we can use the properties
like fields, so here, I can read x
like this, note the icon of x,
is the same icon we have for fields, it's not a method anymore.
So we can read x, and we can also
set it like this. Point dot x and set it to ten.
We don't have to call a method like this, it's a cleaner syntax.
Okay? So this is what properties are for.
If you have private fields, and you want to give maybe a read
only access to the outside, or you want to give the consumer of your classes
the ability to set the values, but you want to have some basic validation,
that's when you use a Property, now in this case, if I want to
give only the read only access to this underline field, I can simply
comment out a setter, so we
call this method a setter, and the other method a getter.
Okay? And now look at this compilation error. We can not change
the value of x. Now let's bring this back
one last thing before we finish this lecture. So here I have used a capital
x with the name of my x property. In JavaScript
and in TypeScript we use Camel Notation to name our fields.
So that's why earlier we defined this
field here using Camel Casing Notation. Camel Casing means
the first letter of the first word is lowercase, and the first letter of
every word after is uppercase. Now, what should we do to
use Camel Casing Notation for our properties? If I name
this the lower case x, it clashes with
the existing field, so let me revert this back,
a convention we use to solve this problem is to prefix
the name of the underlying field with an underline. So, let's rename
this using F2, and prefix it with an underline.
Okay? Now similarly, for the y parameter or the y
field, I'm also going to use underline y,
then we can rename this property from capital x, to lowercase x.
Once again, we press F2, lowercase x,
and note that both instances, both the getter and the
setter are updated. Now,
we can work with this x property exactly the same way
we use the x field. So here's the lesson, the property
looks like a field from the outside, but internally it's really
a method in the class. But more accurately, it's either
one method which is a getter or a setter, or a combination of a getter
and a setter.