Alright, I've
simplified the definition of the point class, I removed the Properties, so
we have a simple Constructor, and the draw method, and we are using this point
class below each definition. Now this is a very simple program with only
one file, but the real world application consists of
tens of hundreds of files. We don't want to write all the code in one file
in main.ts. So ideally, I want to move the definition
of this point class somewhere else, in a file like point.
ts. So here in this project I'm going to add a new file,
point.ts, now
back in main.ts, I'm going to select all this code,
cut it, and move it to point.ts.
Now, in TypeScript, we have this concept called
Modules. Now what a Module is requires a little more explanation
but for now, let me give you a simple, pragmatic definition.
In TypeScript, you can think of each file as a
So in this program we can say we ave two Modules
but this is not quite accurate, because these files are not Modules.
yet. So, in point.ts, we have
defined this class called point, but this is not accessible anywhere
outside this file. So this file defines it's own
scope. In order for us to use this class somewhere else
in our program, we need to export this from the outside.
So, we add the export keyword here, and now this is
visible outside this file. Now that we're exporting
something on top of this file, from TypeScript's point of view this file
is a module, now we need to go back to our main.ts
and import this class, so we can use it. So back in main
.ts, look we have a compilation error,
Cannot find name 'point', because we have not
imported this into main.ts. So on the top,
write import, in curly braces,
we add the name of the types we want to import, in this case, Point.
Now if there are multiple types we want to import, you separate
them using comma. Okay? So,
we import Point from, and here we put the name of
the Module in quotes. What is the name of the module?
It's the relative pass from this file.
So both these files are in the same folder, we can
use period, slash, which refers to the current folder,
and then, point is the name of our module, so it's not
point.ts, look, I got a compilation error.
So, the name of our Module is point. So we no longer have
a compilation error here, and we can create an instance of
this point class and use it. Now, there's a lot more to talk about when it comes
to Modularity in TypeScript, but that's all you need to know for now,
in order to start building applications with Angular. Because
in Angular framework we have a lot of types that are exported,
we need to import these into our TypeScript files and use them.
We're going to see that a lot in this program, the only difference is that
Angular modules are defined in a  different way so we don't add the relative
pass to these Module files, because these files are not really
part of our application. They are somewhere inside node
underline modules folder. So when it comes to importing types defined
in an Angular, we use the library name as the Module name.
For example, one of the libraries is @angular,
/core. Okay? So here is the lesson,
In TypeScript we divide our program into multiple files
in each file, we export one or more types,
these types can be classes, functions, simple
variables or objects, and whenever we need to use these types,
we need to import them first. When we have an import or export statement
on top of a file, that file is a Module from TypeScript's
point of view. In Angular, we also have the concept of Modules,
but Angular Modules are a little bit different, they're not about organization of
code in different files, they are about organization of your application
into smaller, functional areas. We're going to learn about
the Angular modules in the next section.