Art so I've created a new file like that component that he has here I'm going to define a class called
like component and in order to use this outside this class I'm going to explore this.
OK.
Now I wanted to field what is the total number of likes so likes count.
And this is a number.
And the other is a field to determine if the Like button is selected or not.
So it is selected and this is a Lhuillier.
Now we want the consumer of this component to be able to set the initial values for these fields.
So here we need a constructor constructor that takes two parameters like count which is a number and
is select that which is a bullier.
Now here we need to write something like this.
Is that like count we set it to likes count but this is repetitive right.
So I would rather to prefix this parameters with public
and then delete these two fields here.
That's clear.
Next we need a method unclick so human need to check to see if this button is selected or not.
So if this is selected you want to decrease the number of legs so this that likes count minus minus
and then we need to set this that is selected to force that.
Otherwise if the bun is not selected we want to increase the number of lengths so this that looks count
plus plus and this that is selected to true.
So this is the most basic implementation.
What we can do better.
So instead of having this is selected set to false or set to true what we can do we take this out of
these blocks here.
And then at the end we simply toggle this field.
So this is selected.
We said it's not this that is Selecta that's cleaner.
Also we can rewrite this block like this.
So this dad likes count.
We check to see if it's selected is true.
So this is selective.
If that's true we want to increment like count by 1 otherwise we want to incremented by minus 1.
So we can rewrite it like this plus equal one here colon minus one.
So if is select that is true we're going to add 1 to let's count.
Otherwise we're going to add minus 1 to likes count which basically decreases the value of let's count
by 1.
OK.
Now look this is a much cleaner implementation.
With only two lines of code.
So let's go to maned TS here on the top you want to import our class.
So import like component from dot slash like component.
Now we need to create an instance of this class.
So let component equal new like component and here in the constructor we can pass the initial values.
So let's say like count 10 and this is selected then we call component that unclick and finally displayed
the result on the console.
So cancel that log.
Now here in typescript we can use back take and with this we can create a template string like this.
So like count we set this two dollar curly braces and inside curly braces we can add a parameter.
In this case component do not likes count.
So what we put here will be replaced by the value of the likes count field of our component that we
will at is selected.
Once again we add a parameter using dollar sign and curly braces so component dot is selected.
Now honest go to the terminal so tapster compiler start the Ts and then node main.
J.S. So likes count is 11 and is selected is false.
Looks like we have a bug here because back in Maine that as I said the total number of likes to 10 and
is selected to true.
So if the like 1 is selected and we click it again the number of likes should be decreased and is selected
should be false.
So let's go back to our life component OK.
Here's the mistake.
So if you select that is true you want to add minus 1 to let's count otherwise plus 1.
OK.
So back in the terminal one more time OK we got the right result.
Beautiful.
The problem is that before calling the unclick matter I can come here and type component that likes
count said this to let's say two in a real world situation.
This will never happen because let's say a post as initially 10 likes.
So when I click it the number of likes should be 11.
In other words the number of likes should only be changed if we click that like button it shouldn't
magically change.
Otherwise same is true for component.
Dot is selector again.
The value of this field should only be controlled when with click this like component or like man.
So this is where we need to implement a read only property.
So the consumer of this class can not change the value of these two fields.
These two fields their value should only be changed inside the unclick method.
All right.
So backing or like component first I'm going to change the name of these parameters to underline like
count and underline is Selecta.
I'm also going to change their access modifiers to private so we cannot set them from the outside.
And then we need to properties.
So get like count.
And here we return this.
Underline likes count one more property.
So get is selected.
And here we return this underline is selected with this implementation.
If we go back to main the TS We get a compilation error here because we cannot access these private
fields from the outside.
And also if we change these two their properties like lexical and again we get a compilation error because
this is a read only property.
Now where this implementation our component will always be in a valid state.
So finally let's change the name of this field to their properties so we can display them on the console.
All right.
Now back in the terminal when we compile these files look what happens.
We get this error accessors are only available when targeting ECMAScript 5 and higher.
So here we need to pass a switch to typescript compiler so it targets ECMAScript 5.
So TSC start to ts dash dash target and here we add yes 5 and then node maned that Julius OK.
Now the application is working beautifully.
I just want to clarify something before we finish this lecture even though we defined these two properties
here.
In a lot of angular applications we don't really need these and we quite often use fields because the
issue I showed you here about changing the value of these fields directly outside this class that issue
does not happen in English applications because in an English application we bind an element on the
view like you span a paragraph or something to a field in our component.
And with this the value of that field is displayed on the user interface.
So there is no code to directly modify that field modification only happens when the user clicks a button
or trigger some other action.
That raises a dummy that you're going to see that later in this course.