So in case you're an absolute beginner with angular.
Let me quickly explain in two minutes what Engler is and why you should learn it.
And Geller is a framework for building client applications in HD.
Mel CSSA and either java script or a language like typescript that compiles to javascript a typescript
is more common in the end user community because Angleterre itself has been written with typescript.
If you have never worked with Tasca before don't worry at all it's very easy to get familiar with it.
In this course now one question that a lot of beginners have is why do we need angular.
Can we not use plain old javascript or Jey query.
We certainly can and that's how a lot of web applications out there are built.
But as our applications get more complex vanilla javascript or J.A.G. code becomes hard to maintain.
We need a way to properly structure our application.
Sure there are javascript patterns out there that help us with destructuring But these patterns are
hard to understand for a lot of beginners to javascript.
Plus a lot of applications built with vanilla javascript or Jay Cuore are hard to test and that's why
over the past few years various frameworks have been built and evolved to make web application development
easier and gular is an example of such frameworks.
It gives our applications a clean and loosely couple's structure that is easy to understand and easy
to maintain.
It also brings in a lot of utility code that we can reuse in various applications especially when dealing
with the user's navigation and the browser history plus applications built with angular or more testable
so we can easily write automated tests to test various parts of our application.
As I will show you later in the course.
So to answer this question no you don't need a framework like angular to build client applications but
using Engler makes your life a lot easier.