Alright, now that you know what Angular
is, let's take a look at the architecture of Angular applications.
A lot of modern applications have at least two parts,
a front-end and a back-end. The front-end also
called the client, is the part that runs in the web browser
and this is what the user sees and interacts with. So,
it essentially includes the user interface, or UI of an application.
We use HTML, CSS, TypeScript,
and Angular to build the front-end. The back-end sits on a
web server, or multiple web servers on the cloud, and is
responsible for storing the data and doing any kind of processing.
Our front-end, or the client app, talks to the back-end
to get or save the data. One of the questions that a lot of
beginners ask me is, Mosh, how do I save my data in Angular?
Well, you don't, in most cases you don't save the data on the
client, because it can easily disappear as the user clears
the browser data, or moves to a different computer.
That's why we store the data on the server. So here we often have
one or more databases, as well as a bunch of
HTTP services or API's to make this data available to
the clients. In case you don't know, API stands for
Application Programming Interface. Now if you put this
fancy name aside, these HTTP Services, or API's
are essentially end points that are accessible via the HTTP
protocol. So we can call them using simple HTTP
requests, to get or to save the data. If that's
too much technical jargon here, let me give you a metaphor. Think of a port
where ships load or unload. These are
points to get loads in and out of a town, right?
Now imagine these ports are HTTP endpoints, ships
are HTTP requests, and loads are data. So just like
we can send the ship to a port to get some load and bring to us
a client app sends an HTTP request to an endpoint,
to get some data. So this is how the big picture works.
Our web applications have a front-end and a back-end
On the back-end we have more than one databases, and API
is what makes the data available to the clients. For a large
application, around a complex domain, this is where we implement
the business logic of the application, by calculating the
tax and shipping costs, based on various parameters.
The front-end or the client on the other hand, is all about the presentation.
So here we have our HTML templates,
As well as the presentation logic of our application. This
lodging is all about displaying data and responding to user
actions like what should happen when the user clicks on a button
or navigates away from a page. These are examples of
the presentation logic, or the logic that is all about the presentation
aspect of an application. Now in terms of
implementation, building the back-end requires familiarity with other
languages and frameworks, and that's completely outside the scope of
building client apps with Angular. So as an Angular or
front-end developer, you don't have to worry about this. This is the job of
a back-end developer, or full stack developer who knows
both the front-end and the back-end. So for the purpose of this course
we're going to focus on the front-end, and if you want to learn about the back-end,
development you can always pick up a course later down the road
but for now let's just focus on one thing and do it well.