Alright, in this lecture I'm going to show you how to
set up your development environment and create your first Angular
project. So the first thing we need to install is the latest version
of Node. In case you have never worked with Node before,
it's basically a run time environment for executing JavaScript code
outside the browser. In this course we're not going to work with Node,
but Node provides some tools that we need to
build Angular projects. So if you haven't installed Node, head over to node.
js.org, on this page you can see the latest version of Node
for your operating system, so here is the latest stable version
is 6.11, and the latest version is version
8. Now this latest version has more features, but is not
quite stable yet. So go ahead and install the latest
stable version. When you do that, open up the terminal
on Mac, or command prompt on Windows, and type node,
--version. So you can see on my machine,
I'm running Node version 6.10. The minimum
required for building applications is version 6.9.
Once you have Node, then we're going to use a tool called
Node Package Manager, or NPM, to install
third party libraries. One of the libraries we're going to install in this lecture
is Angular CLI, which stands for Command-line
Interface. So it's a Command-line tool, that we use to
create a new Angular project, or generate some boiler plate code
as well as create deployable packages. So once again in
the terminal, you run NMP, install,
-g, which stands for global, and finally the name
of the package, which is @Angular/
cli. If you don't put -g here, Angular
CLI will be installed only in the current folder, and it's not going to be
accessible anywhere else. Now if you're on Mac, you need to put
sudo at the beginning of this command to execute it as an
administrator. Alright next, we need to enter our password,
and now this process is going to take a little while.
Alright, beautiful, we installed Angular CLI.
Now to ensure that the installation was successful,
we can type ng--version.
So again you can see I'm running Angular CLI version 1
.1.0, and below that you can see the version of Node
on my machine. Once again, it's 6.10