So with Angular CLI
in place, now we can create a new Angular project. So
we type ng new, and let's call this project
hello-world.
So this generates a bunch of files and folders, and then
it's going to use NPM to download the third party libraries.
Alright, our project is successfully created.
Now, to start coding we need a code editor.
The editor I'm going to use in this course is Visual Studio Code, or
vs code. It's a beautiful, cross platform
light weight editor, you can download at code.visutalstudio.com.
If you don't like this editor, feel free to use any editors that
you prefer, you can use Sublime, you can use Atom, or any editors.
Now if you're going to use vs code, I want you to add it to
the path, so you can easily open it from the terminal. So here,
if you're using Mac, press Shift, Command, and
P, or if you're using Windows, press Shift, Control,
and P. This opens up the command palette.
Now, here type, code, look at this command here.
Install, code command, in path.
With this we can go to the terminal,
in the folder where we created a new project hello-world, simply type
code, period. So, this opens
vs code, pointing to the current folder. Now in the next lecture, we're going to look at
the structure, you're going to learn what files and folders we have here, but before
we get there, let's make sure that this application works.
So, back in the terminal, once again we use Angular CLI to load
our application in the web server. So we type ng,
space, serve.
So now we have a light development server listening
on local host port 4200, and Angular
CLI also compiled our application, it generated bundles,
for JavaScript and CSS files, so we can open up
Chrome, and head over to localhost, port 4200.
Beautiful! This is our first Angular app.
Next, we're going to look at the structure of our new Angular project.