Alright, now let's see what files and
folders we have in this new project. So the first folder we have here
is e2e, which stands for end to end. And this is where
we write end to end tests for our application. If you have not
worked with end to end tests, these are basically automated tests
that simulate a real user, so we can write code to
launch our browser, navigate to the homepage of our application, click
a few links here and there, fill out a form, click a button, and then
assert that there is something on the page. This is an example of an end to end test.
Now, that's beyond this course, so we don't have to worry about it yet.
Below that we have node_modules. And this is
where we store all the third party libraries that our
application may depend upon. Now this folder is purely for development,
so when we compile our application, parts of this third party libraries
are put in a bundle and deployed with our application.
So we're not going to deploy this node_modules folder to
a server. You're going to see this later in the course. Below that,
we have the src folder. And this is where we have the actual
source code of our application. So we have this app
folder here, and inside this folder here, we have a module
and a component, so every application has at least one module
and one component. You're going to get familiar with these components and modules.
very soon. Below that, we have this assets folder,
where we store the static assets of our application.
So, if we have any image files, any text files, any icons,
all of these, go here. Below that, we have
this environments folder. And this is where we store configuration settings,
for different environments. So we have one file for the production environment,
and the other, for the development environment.
Now, the other files we have in the src folder are favorite icon
which is the icon displayed in the browser, we have index
.html which is a very simple html file that contains
our Angular application, so note that here we don't have any references
to a script or a style sheet. These references will be dynamically
inserted into this page, as I will show you later in this course.
Now below that, we have this main file which is a TypeScript file,
and this is basically the starting point of our application.
So in a lot of programming languages, we have the concept of
the main method, which is the starting point of a program. We have the same
concept in our Angular applications, so all we are doing here is
boot strapping the main module of our application, which is in this case
AppModule, so Angular loads this module
and everything else starts from there. We have this
polyfills file, which basically imports some scripts
that are required for running Angular. Because the Angular framework uses features
of JavaScript that are not available in the current version of JavaScript
supported by most browsers out there. So these polyfills
fill the gap between the features of JavaScript that Angular needs
and the features supported by the current browsers.
Below that we have styles.css, and
this is where we add global styles for our application.
And also each page or each component can have its own styles as you will see
later in the course. Below that we have test.ts
which is basically used for setting up our testing environment.
Again, for now, we don't have to worry about this.
Outside the src folder, you have a configuration folder for Angular cli
its pretty standard configuration, you don't have to worry about this for
the most part, below that we have editorconfig,
so if you're working in a team environment, you want to make sure that
all developers in the team use the same settings in their editors.
So this is where you store the settings. You have this gitignore
file, which is basically for excluding certain files and
folders from your git repository. If you have not worked with git,
don't worry, it's not something that you need to know in order to build applications
with Angular, it's basically a tool for managing and versioning
your source code. Now below that we have karma
.config.js, which is a configuration file
for karma which is a test runner for JavaScript code
Again, we're not going to worry about running tests at this stage. Now below that
we have an imported file, package.json.
This is a standard file that every node project has.
Apart from a bunch of basic settings here, like the name and version of
your application, we have this setting here, dependencies,
which determines the libraries your application is dependent opon
So here you can see we have nine references
to Angular libraries, all these libraries,
start with @angular, and after that we have the name of the library.
So the first library here is for animations, if you're not going to use animations
in your application you can delete this here. So in the future, as
we use third party libraries, you will see them listed here under
the dependencies. Now, below that we also have
another setting or another key called devdependencies.
And these are the libraries that we need in order to develop
this application. So we don't need these to run our application on a production
server, these are purely for a developer machine.
So here we have a reference to angular/cli which we are all familiar with.
We also have a few other references to karma, which is a
again a test runner for JavaScript code. Now below this package that json
we have protractor.config.js,
which is basically a tool for running end to end tests,
for Angular. Again, we're not going to worry about it, and another file here is
tsconfig, which has a bunch of settings for your typescript
compiler. So your TypeScript compiler looks at these settings
and based on these settings is going to compile your TypeScript code into JavaScript
that browsers can understand. Again, for the most part,
you don't have to change any of these here. Just be aware that in the future,
in a complex project, you need to change your TypeScript complier settings,
this is where you need to apply your changes. And finally,
we have tslint.json, which includes a number
of settings for ts links. In case you don't know, tslint
is a static analysis tool for TimeScript code. So
it checks your TypeScript code for readability, maintainability,
and functionality errors. So this is the basic structure of an Angular
project.