Alright, now let's make a timing change to this
application. So in the app folder, open up app
.component.ts. Now
if you have never worked with TypeScript before, don't worry about this code, as we go through
the course, I'm going to break this up for you so you will know exactly what is happening
here. So, all I want you to do here, is to change this
string, from app, to Angular app.
Now, save the file. Back in the terminal,
look at this message, webpack: Compliing...So Angular
SCLI uses a tool called Webpack, which is a billed automation
tool. It gets all of our scripts and style sheets
combines them, puts them in a bundle, and then minifies that bundle,
and this is for optimization. So here you can see we have a few bundles,
like poyfills, which includes all of the scripts to fill the gap,
between the version of the Javascript that Angular needs, and the version of Javascript
supported by most browsers out there. You have main.bundle which
is all the source code of our application, you have styles.bundle
which includes all of our style sheets. And note that here style sheets are actually
stored in the Javascript bundle. You're going to see that in a second.
We also have this vendor.bundle, which includes all the third party
libraries. Now, at the time of recording this video unfortunately Angular
CLI does not allow you to customize the name of
these bundles, or add additional bundles. But there is a discussion going
on in Github, and chances are this may change in the future. Now
that aside, what I want you to note here, is that whenever you change one of your
files, where that file being a style sheet, a typescript file, or
HTML file, web pack automatically recompiles your
application and refreshes your bundles. So now here at
the bottom, you can see webpack: Complied successfully.
Now, if you go back to the browser. Look without me even refreshing
this page, now we have the new title: Welcome to Angular app!!
So this is a feature of web pack called Hot Module Replacement
or Hot Module Reloading, so whenever one of the source files is
modified, Webpack automatically refreshes your browser.
Now, let's try to click on this page, and go to View Page Source.
At the bottom of this page, look at
this script tax. So all the bundles that Webpack generated,
it also injected them into our index
.html. So just to refresh your memory,
here in index.html, look we don't have any references to style
sheet, or script file. So this is something that happens at run time.
So Webpack automatically injects these
scripts into our index.html. Now let's take a look at
this styles.bundle.js. So this
typically what we have here is some javascript, and in the middle of this javascript
code we can find the styles used in your application.
Now how this works is a little bit complicated, so don't worry about it for now,
what I want you to know, is that all of your style sheets are compiled
into a Javascript bundle.