One question that often comes up,
is what's the difference between AngularJS, Angular 2, and
Angular 4, and how did we jump from Angular 2, to Angular 4?
Well, AngularJS was introduced in 2010,
as a JavaScript framework for building client applications.
Soon it gained popularity, and Angular team started
adding new features to the core, but the framework was not designed
with the needs of today's applications in mind. Plus, it was
overly complex, so Angular team decided to rewrite
the original framework using TypeScript, and as a result,
Angular 2 came out in mid 2016. This
new version is entirely different from Angular 1, to the extent
that you can think of it as a completely different framework.
Now, this made a lot of developers unhappy. Because they had a lot of
applications built with Angular 1, with each application over a
few thousand lines of code that had to be rewritten. But over
all, I personally like the direction that Angular team took,
and how they rebuilt Angular with TypeScript. This is a much better
framework, it's a lot cleaner, and it's a lot easier
to understand and work with. Now after a few minor upgrades to Angular 2,
something strange happened. We were up to Angular 2.3,
And then all of a sudden, Angular 4 came out, so a lot of developers
including myself, wondered what happened to Angular 3?
We thought we missed something really big here. But unlike
Angular 2, Angular 4 was not a new framework with a lot of breaking changes,
in fact it wasn't even a major upgrade. So let me explain
what happened, Angular consists of a few different libraries,
that are distributed as separate Node packages by
an NMP, for example, we have the core library that we use
in every Application, we have Angular compiler,
HTTP for calling HTTP services, we have Angular
router for adding navigation to applications, and a few other libraries.
Now all these libraries were versioned the same,
except the router library. So in order to
align these versions and avoid confusion in the future, Angular team
decided to go straight to an Angular version 4. So
in a sense, Angular 4 is not a major upgrade to Angular 2, and you can
think of it as Angular 2.4, as simple as that. Now,
after all this confusion in the community about Angular versions,
the team decided to drop the version suffix and simply call the
framework Angular. So now we have two kinds of Angular,
we have Angular JS, which is the first generation of Angular written
in JavaScript, and it's going to die sooner or later.
And we also have Angular, which refers to Angular 2 or later.
In our discussions, in our articles, and
whenever we ant to talk about Angular 2 or later, we should really use the word
Angular, like I'm an Angular developer, instead of I'm an Angular 2 developer.
Or, I'm an Angular 4 developer. See, it's really wierd.
We should use versions only when we need to talk about this
specific release. For example, when we want to upgrade Angular 4,
to Angular 5, then everybody knows what is the
scope of this upgrade and what are the potential breaking changes that can
impact an application. So this is all about Angular
version history.