So now do you have some basic familiarity with angular.
Let's look at the building blocks of angular apse at the heart of every angle or app.
We have one or more components.
In fact in a real world app we have tens or hundreds of components.
But what is a component a component encapsulates the data the HMO markup and the logic for a view which
is the area of the screen that the user sees.
Let's look at the real world example.
Imagine we're going to build a Web site like you the me.
So on this page we have a navigation bar a sidebar and an area to display the list of courses.
Now we can think of all this as one view or one component or we can break this view into smaller more
maintainable and potentially reusable components like nav bar component side bar component and of course
component.
Similarly in courses component we want to display one or more courses potentially we can break up this
component into smaller components and also to take it to the next level.
Each course component can include a rating component.
Now we can reuse this rating component in multiple places in the same app or in an entirely different
app.
As you see angular embraces component base architecture which allows us to work on smaller and more
maintainable pieces that can also be reused in different places.
So once again a component capturing the data HMO Marco and the logic for a view which is an area of
the screen that the user sees every application has at least one component which we call app component
or root component.
And real world anger is essentially a tree of components starting from the app component or the root
component.
Now in Angleterre we also have another concept called modules.
A module is a container for a group of related components.
Every single or app has at least one module which we call module as your application grows.
You may want to break that module into smaller more maintainable modules.
So you know Eudemus example we can potentially have modules like course module which includes all the
components for displaying courses we can potentially have another module like messaging module which
includes a bunch of components for the area of the Web site where you can send private messages to your
instructors.
We can have an instructor module which includes the components for instructors dashboard that you don't
see and potentially admen module which is the area of the UDP Web site managed by the Eudemus staff.
As an analogy think of a supermarket in a supermarket.
We have different aisles for different products.
We have a section for fruits and vegetables.
We have another section for snacks and other for hardware and so on.
The bigger the supermarket the more aisles we have in a tiny grocery store.
We have probably one or two aisles at the most.
The same applies to our angler hops.
So if you're building a simple application we have only one module which we call the app Argile But
as our application grows in functionality we may need to break that module into smaller modules with
each module responsible for a specific area of our application in that module we have a bunch of related
components.
OK.
So this is the big picture as we go through this course you will learn about these building blocks in
more detail.