All right now let's see this component in action.
There are basically three steps you need to follow in order to use a component.
First you need to create a component.
Second you need to register that component in a module.
And third you need to add an element in your HCM Omarska that show you what I mean by these.
So back backing our first angler project first of all make sure to run and just serve to serve this
application.
So now if you head over to localhost for the two hundred.
This is what you see.
Beautiful.
Now back in Vesco I'm going to create a new component.
So let's open up the fire panel here in the source folder under app.
Yeah I'm going to add the new five.
Now let's imagine.
I want to create a component to display the list of courses.
So look how I named this fire courses dot component dot TS.
This is the convention that we use when building Engler applications that if the name of the component
has multiple wards we separate them using a hyphen.
For example if you're building a component called coarse form you would call this coarse dash form and
then dart component.
Yes.
OK.
So courses that come on in the TS here we start by creating a plain text class so class of course courses
components.
Once again look at the naming convention here.
I'm using the Pascal naming convention.
So the first letter of every word should be capital and also by convention we use the suffix component
in the name of the class.
So here's our class.
In order for Anglo to see this class Erse we need to export is there so far we have only a plain top
secret class.
This is not a component in order to convert this to a component.
We need to add some meta data to read that anger understands.
We use a decorator to achieve this.
In England we have a decorator called component that we can attach to a class to make a class A component.
So first we need to import this decorator on the top.
So import curly braces.
Component from.
Now the name of the library.
So at angular slash core this is the core library of are that you're going to see a lot in this course.
So here we import the component decorator and then when it's applied there is typescript class.
Now look at the syntax rules at same component and then call this like a function.
So this is what we call a decorator function.
Now this function as you see here takes an argument.
So here we pass an object and in this object we add one or more properties to tell angle Engler how
this component works.
For example one property that we use quite often is selector.
So selector and we said this to a CSSA selector.
So in CSSA if I want to reference an element like this I use a selector like this if I want to reference
an element like a div that has a class called coursers by selector would be docked courses.
Right.
And if I want to reference an element with the ID courses this is my selector just basics yes.
OK.
So here we want to reference an element called courses.
Why.
Because with components we can extend H.M.S. vocabulary so we can define new elements like courses and
inside that we will have a list of courses or in the future we can define custom elements a custom HDMI
element called rating and wherever we use that and Giller will render a rating component.
OK so let's delete this selector for just component courses.
Now the second property we add here is template and that's the HDMI markup we want to be rendered or
just component.
Now here I want to render something very simple.
So let's just add an H to element and call these courses in a real world application.
Our templates can be several lines of code.
In that case we can put them in a separate file and I'm going to show you how that works.
Later in the course.
So this is a basic component in angular.
That was the first step.
The second step is to register these components in a module that currently our application has only
one module which we call module.
Let me show you where that is.
So back here in the app folder look we have app that module.
Now once again here we have three import statements on the top.
So nothing special here on the bottom we have a typescript class called app module and note that this
class is decorated with another decorator function called Engy module.
So with this we convert a plain task class to a module from angler's point of view that don't worry
about all these properties here like declarations.
Import providers and bootstrap you're going to learn about them later in the course.
What I wanted to focus on now is this property declarations and this is where we add all the components
that are part of this module.
So by default when we generate an application we have one component called app component and you can
see that component is part of this module.
Now I'm going to add our new component here so coursers component.
So whenever I type the name of a class here and press enter it automatically imported.
On top of my file.
So import coursers component from.
And here's the name of our typescript module.
So period slash which refers to the current folder.
And here's the name of the file.
Of course there's that component.
I know that here we don't have dot ts.
In fact if you add that type of computer it doesn't like that.
So the name of the module is just the name of the file without the extension.
So if you want to add this plug into your vs code simply go here and in the extension of search box
search for auto import.
So I think I'm using our import one point to point to simply install.
And then you'll have to restart the escrowed.
All right so here's our second step.
Now the third step back our component.
So this is the selector for this component which means anywhere we have an element like courses and
it is going to render the template for this component inside that element but where are we going to
add that element.
Let me show you.
So I Kurian the app fuller we have this app called component that HDMI.
This is the external template for our app component.
Let's have a look.
So all this markup you see here is for rendering the home page.
And this is what we get.
Now I want to simplify this.
I'm going to get rid of all this markup at a simple H-1 Corless and Giller and below that I'm going
to add our custom elements courses so when Engler sees this element it's going to render the template
of our coursers component.
Right now back in the browser This is our new home page.
So let's Right-Click this course is aliment and inspect this.
So look what we have here.
We had this H1 and below that we have our courses element and inside this you can see we have the template
for our coursers components.
So this is how angry applications work.
As another example look at this app root element inside the body element raises Taproot.
Well I can the source folder and index that HMO.
So this is the basic template for our application right now inside the body element we have an element
called Dashrath.
This is a custom element because we don't have an element in HMO called Schrute.
So from Anglo's point of view we should have a component with a selector for this element and that's
our app component.
Let's have a look at that.
So back in the app folder let's look at app that component that TS.
So here's our route component our app components look at the selector app Schrute.
So whenever Anglo's sees an element like that it's going to render the template for this component inside
that element.
In this case our template is external.
So we have a template you are l and you can see the name of our template file after each component that
H-G about.
So that's why inside app Dasch wrote here we have the template for app component which includes an H1
and the course is aliment.