All right let's quickly review what we have done so far.
So we created this course is component here.
Then we registered as an app module.
So you're app module we did our component inside the declarations array and then finally use this component
in the template for app component.
So let's quickly review after complaining that it's DMO you added this Course's element here three steps.
OK.
Now there are two problems with this opera.
The first problem is that this approach is a little bit tedious.
There are so many steps.
So first we had to create this typescript class and we had to import this component decorator on the
top and we had to apply it on this task of class.
There is so much boilerplate code here.
Now the second issue is that if you forget the second step or application is going to break.
Let me show you what happens.
So let's go to Aptos module.
I'm going to delete this line here.
Now let's see what happens.
Like in the browser We got a blank page.
So now we need to look at the console tab of chrome developer tools.
So right click anywhere on the page and specked so you can see we have two arrows here you can see the
details of these errors in the console tab.
So here's the error.
Coursers is not in known element.
So if you don't register a component in a module Angerer doesn't know about it and it doesn't know what
to do with this Course's element because this is not a native HDMI element.
So now let me show you a quicker and more reliable way to create an angle on a component.
We need to go back to the terminal but look our terminal is always busy.
It's serving the application so we either have to open a new terminal window or we can actually open
a terminal window inside.
SCOTT So back here if you press control and back tick which is the character before the number one on
your keyboard look we have a terminal window here and this is much easier to access and going back and
forth between different windows.
So here we can use angular Seelye to generate a component.
So just like how we generated an application with Engy new we can also generate a component with this
N-G.
So the syntax is like this in the space G which is short for generate and see which is short for component
and then the name of the component.
Let's say we want to create a component called course.
So of course because what happened and I created a directory called course and inside this directory
added four fires.
S.c.s this file for storing style sheets for a component an HMO file for storing the template a spec
file which is for writing unit tests for that component.
And finally a typescript file which is the actual component itself.
Now what is interesting here is that it also updated apt at module and registered this new component.
Let's have a look.
So we can close the terminal window using the same shortcut which is control and back take now we can
open the files panel using command and be on Mac or control B on Windows OK.
Look at.
After module.
So look inside the declarations array.
Now we have of course component.
So this way we don't have to remember to come back here and register our new components before we move
on.
Let me just quickly add our of course is a component that I removed earlier R.K. now in the files panel
this is the folder for our new component so this will or we have this for us.
Now let's take a look at the typescript class.
It has all the boilerplate code that we wrote earlier plus a little bit more.
So here we are importing the component decorator and honest which is an interface we're going to look
at this later and of course we have this component decorator applied to our typescript class.
We have a selector we have the u r L r r a template file as well as a u r l or a stylesheet file so
anger Seelye saves us a lot of time.
Now as we go through this course I'll show you how we can use this tool to generate other building blocks
for your applications.