So earlier I told you that a component encapsulates the data the logic and the HMO markup for a view.
So in this example in our courses component we have HMO markup but we don't have any data or any logic.
So let's extend this example and take it to the next level.
I want to define a field in this class to hold the title of this page so title I'm going to set this
to List Of course this.
Now I want to display this title in our template dynamically so I'm going to remove this hardcoded label
here it angular.
We have this special syntax double curly braces and we use this to render something in our template
dynamically.
So here I can put this title field.
This expression will be evaluated at runtime and the value of this title field will be placed in our
dorm.
Now if the value of the title field changes at some point in the future angular will automatically update
the DOM.
This is one of the beauties of Ingela framework.
So here we have this concept of data binding.
So we're binding our view to have filled in this component whenever the value of that field changes.
The view is automatically notified and updated right now let's save the changes back in the browser.
All right here's our new title.
Beautiful.
Now back here we don't always have to put the name of Phil here.
We can write any simple javascript expressions.
For example I can put a string here.
Title column and then concatenate this with our title field.
Save like this is our new title.
Here we can also call a method in this class to get some value.
For example I've modified a method get title and here I'm going to return this the title now here we
can simply call our new method get title like this and we'll get the exact same result.
There you go.
This of course is so this special syntax year we call it strange.
In the next lecture I'm going to show you how to render a list of courses here.