All right.
Now let's take this example to the next level instead of displaying a simple title field you want to
display the list of courses.
So first when is a field to hold a list or courses.
So courses we said this to an airy with three items.
Of course one of course two and course three.
Now this is a simplified example.
In a real world application instead of simple strings here you would have objects but don't worry we're
going to get there.
Now I want to display these in our template how should we do that.
First we need to change this single code to the back take character so delete tactic acting is the character
before.
Number one on your keyboard.
That may change just as well.
Now the benefit of using the back tick is that we can break up this template into multiple lines and
make it more readable.
So I want to put this H-2 here and below that I want to add a UL and a bunch of list item elements like
this.
Now I want to repeat this lie for each course.
Now for that we need to use one of the angular building blocks called directive.
We use directives to manipulate the DOM.
We can use them to add a dom element or remove an existing dumb element or change to a class of a dom
element or its style and so on.
So here you're going to use a special directive called Engy for use it like an attribute in extrema.
So we set it to a string.
And here we are going to write some expression now before going any further.
We should prefix this attribute with an asterisk.
It's a special syntax.
Angular.
So whenever you're using a directive that modifies the structure of a dom you should prefix that directive
with an asterisk.
In case you're curious about the reason I have covered it.
Later in the section about directives.
So for now just remember whenever you are using a directive that modifies the structure of the dom by
adding or removing an element you need to prefix that with an asterisk.
Now here we want to write an expression similar to what you write in for each blocks so let.
Course of courses.
What does this mean with the left key word we are defining invaluable so the names are valuable as course.
This is like a loop variable in javascript.
All is a special keyword and courses is the field in this class that you are iterating over.
So when you receive this expression it's going to iterate over the Course's field and in each iteration.
This course variable will hold the value of one course at a time.
Now inside this list I know you want to display this course.
So once again we use string interpolation.
Double curly braces.
And add this course variable here.
Let's look at the result.
Save can the browser and here we have the list of workhorses beautiful.
Now in most real world applications we get these courses from the server and for that we need to use
another building block of Angella called a service and that's the topic for the next lecture.