Right now we have the list of course is here.
But in a real world application most of the time we get these courses from the server.
So it's sort of hard coding them here.
We need to call in HTP and point to get the list of courses.
Now here we have two options.
One is to add the logic for calling an HTP service here in this component.
But there are a couple of problems with this approach.
The first problem is that this logic is going to tightly coupled this component to that HTP endpoint
in the future when you want to write unit tests for this class.
We don't want to be dependent upon a live HTP endpoint because this is going to make it harder to execute
those unit tests.
So we want to create a fake implementation of an age type service.
So this is the first issue with writing this logic inside this class inside this component.
It's going to tightly coupled this component to that age and point.
The second issue is that maybe somewhere else in the application we're going to have another page where
we display the list of courses.
Maybe it's part of a dashboard maybe somewhere for an admin with this implementation.
We have to repeat this logic the logic for consuming that is the type of service in multiple places
and that's not good.
And finally the third issue with this implementation is that the components should not include any logic
other than the presentation logic.
What is the logic behind this view.
What should happen when we clicked upon when we select an item from a dropdown list and so on.
Details of how courses are retrieved should be delegated somewhere else in our application.
So where should we implement that logic in angular.
We use services for that.
So are we going to define a separate class which we call a service.
And there will at this logic forgetting the list of courses from an HDTV service then we can reuse this
class in multiple places.
So let me show you how to do that hearing the app folder.
I'm going to add in your file.
Now look at the naming convention coursers dot service TS So the name of our service is courses and
by convention we have the word service in the file name.
And finally that TS When creating a component we use coursers those component ts.
So not the difference.
Now here once again we want to export a plain type strip class so export class coursers service.
So once again by convention we add the word service as a suffix and the class name.
Now when creating components we decorate this class with the component decorator remember component
but in Angola we don't have a decorator for services so a service is essentially a plain typescript
class.
So delete now here we want to add a method for getting the list of courses.
Get courses.
For now we don't want to get distracted with the complexity of consuming and HTP service.
So let's just return the same array that we had in our component and later I will show you how to consume
an HDTV service.
So back in our component
I'm going to select this right here.
Got back into service and simply return it from the Smethurst.
Now imagine here in this method that we have that logic for consuming and the type of service with this
implementation we can reuse this class.
We can reuse this logic in multiple places in our application.
And also this will separate or decouple our component from this logic.
So back in our component here we're not going to have any logic for consuming an extra service.
And this allows us to uniters this class without dependency upon that HTP endpoint.
So while unit testing in this class we can provide a fake implementation of that service if that's too
complicated.
Don't worry about it.
Unit testing is something for the future.
OK now we have a service we need to use the service in our component.
How.
That's the topic for the next lecture.