Okay now we have a service to get the list of courses from the server.
We need to use this service and this course is component.
So first we need to add a constructor here constructor because a constructor is where we initialize
an object.
So here we need to create an instance of our course of service something like this.
Let service be new courses service.
Once again I'm using the auto import plug in.
So when I press enter it automatically adds the import statement here on the top.
So import course the service from current folder coursers dot service.
All right now back in the constructor.
So we have a service and then we can initialize this course is field like this.
This of course this we said to service that get coursers.
Let's test the application and make sure everything works.
Up to this point save Ok we get the same list.
Beautiful.
However there is a problem with its implementation.
The first problem is that by using this new operator here we have tightly coupled this course this component
to the course of service.
So this is exactly like the problem we had earlier if we implemented the logic for consuming and the
tipis service inside this component we wouldn't be able to unit test this class.
Now we put this logic in a different class of course of service but because we're directly creating
an instance of this class here we're still tightly coupled to that implementation.
The other issue here is that if in the future we decide to add a parameter to the constructor of course
or service we have to come back here and anywhere else in our application where we have used this course
of service and add a new argument like one.
So any time we change the constructor of the service we end up with multiple changes in our application
code.
So this is very fragile.
So what should we do.
Well instead of we creating an instance of the course of service we can ask Engler to do that for us
so we can delete this line here.
And add a parameter in the constructor call it service off type courses.
So Chris with this when anger is going to create an instance or a component it looks at this constructor
it is that this constructor has a dependency.
This dependency is of type courses service.
So first it creates an instance of the course of service and then passes that to the constructor.
Now with this implementation if you change the constructor of course a service and add a new parameter.
We don't have to modify 100 places in our code to reflect the change angular will automatically instantiate
a new course or service object.
The second benefit of this implementation is that when we are going to unit test this course is a component
instead of supplying an actual course of service to this constructor.
We can create a fake implementation of this service that doesn't use that HTP service on the backend.
In other words we have decoupled our course component from courses service.
So here's the lesson.
When you use the new operator like this inside a class you have tightly coupled your class to that implementation.
You cannot change this at runtime but when you add that dependency as a parameter of a constructor you
have decoupled the class from that dependency.
Now we're not done yet.
We need to construct angular to create an instance of course a service and pass it to our coarsest component.
This concept is called dependency injection.
So we should instruct Engler to inject the dependences of this component into its constructor.
Simple as that.
That's dependency injection.
A lot of people think dependency injection is so complicated but it's really a $25 term for a five cent
concept.
So Dependency Injection means injecting or providing the dependencies on class into its constructor.
Now angular as a dependency injection framework built into it.
So when it's going to create an instance of a component it can inject that dependencies.
But in order for that to work we need to register these dependencies somewhere in our model.
So let's see if that changes.
Now we need to go to our app module.
So here is apt on module okay.
Look at this engine module decorator.
Here we have a property called providers which is set to an empty array in this array.
We need to register all the dependencies that components in this module are dependent upon for example
our courses component is dependent upon of course the service.
So we need to register course a service as a provider in this module.
So
here I'm going at courses service if you forget the step dependency injection is not going to work.
Let me show you what happens.
So I'm going to comment out this line.
Save the browser get a blank page.
So that means something is wrong.
Let's open up chrome developer tools which shift command and I on Mac or shift control eye on Windows.
Look at this error.
No provider for course a service this is an error that you might see quite often when building angular
apps.
So the error is telling us that we have not registered course a service as a provider in our module.
So backing up module I'm going to have this course of service here save can the browser and we have
the list of courses.
Now one more thing before we finish this lecture.
When you register a dependency as a provider in a module Engler will create a single instance of that
class or that entire module.
So imagine in this module we have 100 components and 50 of these components need the course of service
in the memory we're going to have only a single instance of course a service and anger will pass the
same instance.
All of its components.
This is what we call the singleton pattern.
So a single instance of a given object exists in the memory.
So a quick round up backing or a component we added course courses service as a prompter and the constructor.
Or in other words as a dependency of this class and then registered this as a provider in our app module
with this implementation.
When anger is going to create an instance of this component first it will instantiate its dependencies
and then it will inject those dependencies into the constructor of this class.
And this is what we call dependency injection.