All right.
Now let me show you a quick way to create a service in Angola.
So we go to the terminal.
Once again you can switch to the terminal window or you can press control and back take in fiascoes.
So here we have a small terminal window.
We're going to use Engler Seelye generate a service so n g g or generate.
Previously we use C for components.
Now we're going to use as our services imagine we're going to create a service for sending emails.
This service is going to call an end point somewhere.
We're sending these e-mails.
So let's call this e-mail.
I know that here I just add the service name.
I don't need to add dot service.
OK.
So this generates two fires for us.
One is the actual service file and the other is a spec file which includes some boilerplate code for
writing unit tests for that service.
So in the app folder look here's our news service e-mail that serviced a TS.
So we have a plane typescript class called email service but there is something extra here that you
didn't see before.
We have this injectable which is another decorator function similar to the component decorator function.
Why do we need this here.
You would need this decorator only if this service had dependencies in its constructor.
For example imagine here we had a dependency lock log service of type log service.
In this case we need to apply these injectable decorator function on this class.
And this tells angular that this class is an injectable class which means angular should be able to
inject dependencies of this class into its constructor.
Now we didn't use this decorator when defining components because when we use the component decorator
that decorator internally includes these injectable decorator.
So that's all about injectable.
And by the way note that this decorator function is defined in angular slushed core library.